http://www.worldgbc.org/privacy-policy

Skip to main content
Home > Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy This page exists to explain how we may use your personal data, as members, sponsors, partners and service providers of WorldGBC.
If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact, office@worldgbc.org, or at our postal address: WorldGBC, The Building Centre, 26 Store Street, London, WC1E 7BT, United Kingdom.
What is the World Green Building Council?
The World Green Building Council (‘WorldGBC’, ‘our’, ‘we’ or ‘us’) is a global network of Green Building Councils in over 70 countries which is transforming the places we live, work, play and learn. Buildings are diverse and beautiful, but they must also be sustainable. We believe green buildings can and must be at the centre of our lives. Our changing climate means we must reshape the way we grow and build. Our mission is to create green buildings for everyone, everywhere - enabling people to thrive both today and tomorrow. By taking action, we champion local and global leadership. We empower our community to drive change. We are greater than the sum of our parts, and commit to green buildings for everyone, everywhere.
How is the information collected by us?
Members, Sponsors, Partners and Service Providers
Most of our contact data is made up of employees of our member organisations; partners, sponsors and service providers, collected in the first instance via the application form on joining WorldGBC in any of those capabilities. We also send out regular ‘contact update’ forms to our primary contacts at our member, sponsors, partners and services provider organisations. This data is volunteered by our primary contacts as individuals who may wish to receive WorldGBC member, sponsors and partners benefits – news, event invitations and learning and networking opportunities. We may also obtain the contact details of individuals that work for our member, partners, sponsors or service providers organisations via event booking pages, various webforms and email sign-ups.
Non-Members
Sometimes we may obtain the personal data of individuals outside of our member, partners, sponsors and service providers network, for several reasons:
Working on projects with stakeholders outside of the membership, partnership, or sponsorship
It may be given to us at events or trade shows where the individual has expressed an interest in joining WorldGBC or future collaboration
It may be obtained from the public domain as a prospective WorldGBC member, partners, sponsor or service provider
It may be volunteered to us by existing members, partners sponsors or service providers
Sometimes non-WorldGBC members may volunteer their data via webforms, booking pages, email sign-ups etc.
What type of information is collected from you?
The personal information we collect might include your name, job title, business email address, business address and business telephone numbers. We also collect information on ways in which you have interacted with WorldGBC, for instance email content, email opens and click throughs, event attendance, participations on meetings, etc. Job applicants’ personal data collected would be consistent with recruitment norms, for instance personal address, telephone numbers, email addresses, curriculum vitae etc.
How is your information used?
We may use your information to:
To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into by you and us, ie. on delivery of our member benefits, billing etc.
To assess how engaged our member organisations are
To notify you of changes to our services
To send you communications which you have requested and that may be of interest or are related to your work
To promote our events, meetings, and work
To process a job application
To communicate to existing employees on work matters
We will never retain personal information beyond what is necessary to deliver relevant activity or as long as is set out in any relevant contracts between us. We are legally required to hold some types of information to fulfil our statutory obligations.
Who do we share information with?
We will never share personal information with a third party for the purposes of marketing unless given prior consent.
We do share personal information with some third parties in the process of providing our services, for instance with some members, agents, IT providers and other subcontractors. Some of these parties may be outside of the European Union (EU) in which cases they are not subject to the same high legislation standards as inside the EU. By submitting personal data to us, you are agreeing to its processing by these parties. However, steps will be taken by WorldGBC to ensure that the same standards of privacy are adhered to, equal to those outlined in this document.
What are your choices?
On collection of your personal data via any of the aforementioned means, we will always give you the option to choose whether you receive information from us about our activity, industry news, event invitations etc. You also have the right to opt out of communications or have your personal information deleted from our records at any time, unless we have a legal obligation to retain it. This can be done via info@worldgbc.org or our postal address: WorldGBC, The Building Centre, 26 Store Street, London, WC1E 7BT, United Kingdom.
How can you update your information?
We regularly contact our members to ensure we are holding accurate information, but you can also contact us at any time to update us. You have the right to request any information we hold about you. Again, please contact office@worldgbc.org or via our postal address: WorldGBC, The Building Centre, 26 Store Street, London, WC1E 7BT, United Kingdom.
Security
We will always ensure that your information is kept secure and all electronic data – email accounts, databases and devices are protected by regularly updated passwords. Some non-sensitive data is transmitted over the internet and is outside of our control (emails for instance) for which we can never guarantee complete security. We never ask you to share your password.
Data Profiling
We may analyse your personal data to assess your interactions with us or to help us identify areas of our work that may be of specific interest to you. You may receive communications from us based on these analytics.
Use of ‘cookies’
A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of your computer’s hard disk so that the website can recognise your computer. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the “lifetime” of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. When you visit our website, we send you a cookie.
We use cookies to ensure that you receive the best experience from our website, to recognise that you are a repeat visitor and to ensure that all areas of our website work for you. If you continue without changing your cookie settings, we will assume that you are happy to receive the cookies that we use. You may change your cookie settings at any time but if you choose to do so, some elements of our website will not work correctly.
Links
Our website may contain links to other organisations’ sites. We have no control over how your data is used by these organisations, so we would urge you to look at their own privacy statements if you have any concerns.
This Privacy Policy was last updated in April 2018.
This page exists to explain how we may use your personal data, as members, sponsors, partners and service providers of WorldGBC.
If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please contact, office@worldgbc.org, or at our postal address: WorldGBC, The Building Centre, 26 Store Street, London, WC1E 7BT, United Kingdom.
What is the World Green Building Council?
The World Green Building Council (‘WorldGBC’, ‘our’, ‘we’ or ‘us’) is a global network of Green Building Councils in over 70 countries which is transforming the places we live, work, play and learn. Buildings are diverse and beautiful, but they must also be sustainable. We believe green buildings can and must be at the centre of our lives. Our changing climate means we must reshape the way we grow and build. Our mission is to create green buildings for everyone, everywhere - enabling people to thrive both today and tomorrow. By taking action, we champion local and global leadership. We empower our community to drive change. We are greater than the sum of our parts, and commit to green buildings for everyone, everywhere.
How is the information collected by us?
Members, Sponsors, Partners and Service Providers
Most of our contact data is made up of employees of our member organisations; partners, sponsors and service providers, collected in the first instance via the application form on joining WorldGBC in any of those capabilities. We also send out regular ‘contact update’ forms to our primary contacts at our member, sponsors, partners and services provider organisations. This data is volunteered by our primary contacts as individuals who may wish to receive WorldGBC member, sponsors and partners benefits – news, event invitations and learning and networking opportunities. We may also obtain the contact details of individuals that work for our member, partners, sponsors or service providers organisations via event booking pages, various webforms and email sign-ups.
Non-Members
Sometimes we may obtain the personal data of individuals outside of our member, partners, sponsors and service providers network, for several reasons:
Working on projects with stakeholders outside of the membership, partnership, or sponsorship
It may be given to us at events or trade shows where the individual has expressed an interest in joining WorldGBC or future collaboration
It may be obtained from the public domain as a prospective WorldGBC member, partners, sponsor or service provider
It may be volunteered to us by existing members, partners sponsors or service providers
Sometimes non-WorldGBC members may volunteer their data via webforms, booking pages, email sign-ups etc.
What type of information is collected from you?
The personal information we collect might include your name, job title, business email address, business address and business telephone numbers. We also collect information on ways in which you have interacted with WorldGBC, for instance email content, email opens and click throughs, event attendance, participations on meetings, etc. Job applicants’ personal data collected would be consistent with recruitment norms, for instance personal address, telephone numbers, email addresses, curriculum vitae etc.
How is your information used?
We may use your information to:
To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into by you and us, ie. on delivery of our member benefits, billing etc.
To assess how engaged our member organisations are
To notify you of changes to our services
To send you communications which you have requested and that may be of interest or are related to your work
To promote our events, meetings, and work
To process a job application
To communicate to existing employees on work matters
We will never retain personal information beyond what is necessary to deliver relevant activity or as long as is set out in any relevant contracts between us. We are legally required to hold some types of information to fulfil our statutory obligations.
Who do we share information with?
We will never share personal information with a third party for the purposes of marketing unless given prior consent.
We do share personal information with some third parties in the process of providing our services, for instance with some members, agents, IT providers and other subcontractors. Some of these parties may be outside of the European Union (EU) in which cases they are not subject to the same high legislation standards as inside the EU. By submitting personal data to us, you are agreeing to its processing by these parties. However, steps will be taken by WorldGBC to ensure that the same standards of privacy are adhered to, equal to those outlined in this document.
What are your choices?
On collection of your personal data via any of the aforementioned means, we will always give you the option to choose whether you receive information from us about our activity, industry news, event invitations etc. You also have the right to opt out of communications or have your personal information deleted from our records at any time, unless we have a legal obligation to retain it. This can be done via info@worldgbc.org or our postal address: WorldGBC, The Building Centre, 26 Store Street, London, WC1E 7BT, United Kingdom.
How can you update your information?
We regularly contact our members to ensure we are holding accurate information, but you can also contact us at any time to update us. You have the right to request any information we hold about you. Again, please contact office@worldgbc.org or via our postal address: WorldGBC, The Building Centre, 26 Store Street, London, WC1E 7BT, United Kingdom.
Security
We will always ensure that your information is kept secure and all electronic data – email accounts, databases and devices are protected by regularly updated passwords. Some non-sensitive data is transmitted over the internet and is outside of our control (emails for instance) for which we can never guarantee complete security. We never ask you to share your password.
Data Profiling
We may analyse your personal data to assess your interactions with us or to help us identify areas of our work that may be of specific interest to you. You may receive communications from us based on these analytics.
Use of ‘cookies’
A cookie is a text-only string of information that a website transfers to the cookie file of your computer’s hard disk so that the website can recognise your computer. A cookie will typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the “lifetime” of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number. When you visit our website, we send you a cookie.
We use cookies to ensure that you receive the best experience from our website, to recognise that you are a repeat visitor and to ensure that all areas of our website work for you. If you continue without changing your cookie settings, we will assume that you are happy to receive the cookies that we use. You may change your cookie settings at any time but if you choose to do so, some elements of our website will not work correctly.
Links
Our website may contain links to other organisations’ sites. We have no control over how your data is used by these organisations, so we would urge you to look at their own privacy statements if you have any concerns.
This Privacy Policy was last updated in April 2018.
Share
Share
All Categories
About Green Building What is green building?
